<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>

    <!-- Category Titles -->
    <string name="preventive_advice_category_title">Preventive Advice</string>
    <string name="support_advice_category_title">Helping a Friend</string>
    <string name="family_advice_category_title">Talking to My Family</string>

    <!-- Preventive Advice Cards -->
    <string name="preventive_advice_title_1">
        Set Clear Boundaries
    </string>
    <string name="preventive_advice_text_1">
        Establishing clear personal boundaries helps you stay focused and prioritize activities
        that support your well-being. Setting these boundaries also involves recognizing your
        own limits and making intentional choices to avoid environments or social situations
        where addictive substances or behaviors are present. Communicate your boundaries with
        friends and family to gain their support and avoid misunderstandings.
    </string>

    <string name="preventive_advice_title_2">
        Build a Support Network
    </string>
    <string name="preventive_advice_text_2">
        Surround yourself with friends, family, and mentors who encourage healthy
        habits and are there to support you through challenges. A strong support network
        can remind you of your goals and help you resist temptations during difficult times.
        Don’t hesitate to seek advice from those who have successfully avoided or overcome
        addictions, as they can provide valuable insights and encouragement.
    </string>

    <string name="preventive_advice_title_3">
        Develop Healthy Coping Mechanisms
    </string>
    <string name="preventive_advice_text_3">
        Stress and emotions can lead to unhealthy behaviors if not managed well.
        Instead of turning to substances, try cultivating practices like mindfulness,
        physical activity, or creative outlets such as art, writing, or music. These healthy
        coping mechanisms can provide a constructive way to release stress and manage emotions,
        ultimately supporting your journey toward a balanced lifestyle
    </string>

    <string name="preventive_advice_title_4">
        Educate Yourself
    </string>
    <string name="preventive_advice_text_4">
        Understanding the risks associated with addictive behaviors enables you to make
        informed choices and recognize warning signs early on. Educate yourself on how
        different substances or habits can impact your physical health, mental well-being,
        and personal relationships. Awareness can empower you to make conscious decisions
        that align with your goals and values.
    </string>

    <string name="preventive_advice_title_5">
        Set Personal Goals
    </string>
    <string name="preventive_advice_text_5">
        Setting clear, achievable goals—both short-term and long-term—gives your
        life purpose and direction. By focusing on meaningful activities,
        you build a life that reflects your values and aspirations. Pursue
        accomplishments that foster personal growth, whether that’s developing
        new skills, improving relationships, or working towards career milestones.
    </string>

    <!-- Support Advice Cards -->
    <string name="support_advice_title_1">
        Be a Good Listener
    </string>
    <string name="support_advice_text_1">
        Sometimes, the best way to support someone is by simply listening.
        Let your friend know you’re there for them by being present and offering
        them a safe space to express their feelings without judgment. Avoid offering
        solutions too quickly, and instead, listen attentively to what they’re experiencing
        and reassure them that they’re not alone.
    </string>

    <string name="support_advice_title_2">
        Avoid Enabling Behaviors
    </string>
    <string name="support_advice_text_2">
        Supporting a friend doesn’t mean encouraging harmful behavior. Avoid
        actions that might unintentionally enable their addiction, such as excusing
        harmful behavior or helping them obtain addictive substances. Instead, encourage
        healthy habits and set firm boundaries. Let your friend know you care while promoting
        positive change.
    </string>

    <string name="support_advice_title_3">
        Offer Positive Encouragement
    </string>
    <string name="support_advice_text_3">
        Help your friend stay motivated by acknowledging their strengths and celebrating
        their accomplishments, no matter how small. Positive encouragement can reinforce
        their self-worth and make them feel supported as they work toward recovery.
        Remind them of past successes and reassure them that progress is possible.
    </string>

    <string name="support_advice_title_4">
        Educate Yourself About Addiction
    </string>
    <string name="support_advice_text_4">
        Understanding addiction can enable you to offer more informed support.
        Learn about the signs, triggers, and available resources, so you can respond
        effectively if your friend seeks your help. This knowledge can also prevent
        misunderstandings and help you communicate compassionately and constructively.
    </string>

    <string name="support_advice_title_5">
        Encourage Professional Help
    </string>
    <string name="support_advice_text_5">
        If your friend is struggling, gently suggest that they consider professional support,
        such as counseling, therapy, or a support group. Offer to accompany them to
        their first session if it would make them feel more comfortable. Seeking help can
        be intimidating, but knowing they’re not alone can make a world of difference.
    </string>

    <!-- Family Advice Cards -->
    <string name="family_advice_title_1">
        Prepare What You Want to Say
    </string>
    <string name="family_advice_text_1">
        Take time to plan what you want to communicate to your family.
        Think about the points you want to express and the emotions you wish to convey.
        Be honest about your struggles, and share specific ways their support can help.
        This clarity can create a more productive conversation and encourage understanding.
    </string>

    <string name="family_advice_title_2">
        Choose the Right Moment
    </string>
    <string name="family_advice_text_2">
        Find a calm and private setting where you can speak openly without distractions.
        Avoid initiating the conversation when tensions are high or during busy times.
        Choose a moment when your family members are available and willing to listen,
        making it easier for them to engage fully with your message.
    </string>

    <string name="family_advice_title_3">
        Express Your Feelings
    </string>
    <string name="family_advice_text_3">
        Be open about how addiction has impacted you physically, emotionally, and socially.
        Let your family know why you need their support and what it means to you.
        This honesty can foster empathy and help your family understand the importance
        of their role in your journey.
    </string>

    <string name="family_advice_title_4">
        Be Open to Their Reactions
    </string>
    <string name="family_advice_text_4">
        Your family members may respond with a range of emotions, including concern,
        confusion, or frustration. Be prepared to listen to their responses
        without getting defensive. Give them space to ask questions so they can
        better understand your situation and how they might be able to support you.
    </string>

    <string name="family_advice_title_5">
        Ask for Their Support
    </string>
    <string name="family_advice_text_5">
        Explain to your family how they can help, whether by attending counseling sessions,
        resources together, or simply being there when you need someone to talk to.
        Acknowledge that their support can make a difference, and express gratitude for
        any help they’re willing to provide.
    </string>

</resources>
