<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>

    <!-- Category Titles -->
    <string name="preventive_advice_category_title">Preventive Advice</string>
    <string name="support_advice_category_title">Helping a Friend</string>
    <string name="family_advice_category_title">Talking to My Family About My Addictions</string>

    <!-- Preventive Advice Cards -->
    <string name="preventive_advice_title_1">
        Set Clear Boundaries
    </string>
    <string name="preventive_advice_text_1">
        Establishing clear personal boundaries helps you stay focused and prioritize activities
        that support your well-being. Avoid environments and situations where
        addictive substances are present.
    </string>

    <string name="preventive_advice_title_2">
        Build a Support Network
    </string>
    <string name="preventive_advice_text_2">
        Surround yourself with friends and mentors who encourage
        healthy habits. A strong support network is essential for staying motivated
        and avoiding temptation.
    </string>

    <string name="preventive_advice_title_3">
        Develop Healthy Coping Mechanisms
    </string>
    <string name="preventive_advice_text_3">
        Stress and emotions can lead to unhealthy behaviors. Practice mindfulness,
        physical activity, or creative outlets as healthy ways to cope with stress
        and emotional challenges.
    </string>

    <string name="preventive_advice_title_4">
        Educate Yourself
    </string>
    <string name="preventive_advice_text_4">
        Understanding the risks associated with addictive behaviors helps you make
        informed choices. Stay aware of how substances or habits can affect your
        body and mind.
    </string>

    <string name="preventive_advice_title_5">
        Set Personal Goals
    </string>
    <string name="preventive_advice_text_5">
        Establishing short- and long-term goals gives you a sense of purpose and direction.
        Focus on activities and achievements that bring value and growth to your life.
    </string>

    <!-- Support Advice Cards -->
    <string name="support_advice_title_1">
        Be a Good Listener
    </string>
    <string name="support_advice_text_1">
        Sometimes, just being there and actively listening can make a big difference.
        Let your friend express their feelings without judgment or interruptions.
    </string>

    <string name="support_advice_title_2">
        Avoid Enabling Behaviors
    </string>
    <string name="support_advice_text_2">
        It’s important to support your friend without enabling their addictive behavior.
        Set clear boundaries and encourage them to seek professional help when needed.
    </string>

    <string name="support_advice_title_3">
        Offer Positive Encouragement
    </string>
    <string name="support_advice_text_3">
        Motivate your friend by focusing on their strengths and achievements.
        Remind them of their value and support their positive steps toward recovery.
    </string>

    <string name="support_advice_title_4">
        Educate Yourself About Addiction
    </string>
    <string name="support_advice_text_4">
        Understanding addiction can help you better support your friend.
        Learn about the signs, triggers, and resources available to provide informed
        advice and assistance.
    </string>

    <string name="support_advice_title_5">
        Encourage Professional Help
    </string>
    <string name="support_advice_text_5">
        If your friend is struggling, gently encourage them to seek help from a
        counselor, therapist, or support group. Offer to accompany them to make the
        process less intimidating.
    </string>

    <!-- Family Advice Cards -->
    <string name="family_advice_title_1">
        Prepare What You Want to Say
    </string>
    <string name="family_advice_text_1">
        Take time to reflect on what you want to communicate to your family. Be honest
        about your struggles and explain how their support can make a difference.
    </string>

    <string name="family_advice_title_2">
        Choose the Right Moment
    </string>
    <string name="family_advice_text_2">
        Find a calm, private setting where you can speak openly without distractions.
        Make sure it’s a time when your family members are available and receptive to talking.
    </string>

    <string name="family_advice_title_3">
        Express Your Feelings
    </string>
    <string name="family_advice_text_3">
        Share how your addiction has affected you emotionally and physically.
        Let your family know how you feel and why you’re seeking their understanding and help.
    </string>

    <string name="family_advice_title_4">
        Be Open to Their Reactions
    </string>
    <string name="family_advice_text_4">
        Your family may have a range of emotions, from concern to confusion. Be patient
        and open to their reactions, and let them ask questions so they can better understand your situation.
    </string>

    <string name="family_advice_title_5">
        Ask for Their Support
    </string>
    <string name="family_advice_text_5">
        Let your family know how they can support you, whether it’s attending counseling sessions with you,
        helping you find resources, or simply being there to listen. Show appreciation for their willingness to help.
    </string>

</resources>
